ZACHARY UPSTONE

Email o GitHub o LinkedIn o Website

Personal Profile

I am a recent graduate with a 1st in Computer Science from the University of Bath. I have experience working in both software development and quality assurance at BSQUARE, an IoT solutions company. From this, I also gained experience working within a team in an agile environment, developing my communication skills. I also have experience working with multiple customer-facing job at McDonald's and a bar, making me into an adaptable and enthusiastic worker who is good at handling people. I am also a team worker having experience working on group projects throughout university.

Professional Experience

PugpigProduct Developer

London, UK 10/2024 - Present

- Worked on web code adding new features and fixing bugs, including localisation and controllable theming work.
- Worked on native code adding custom SDK's, redesign features and introducing new functionality.
- Worked on backend code including express, managing the theming, localisation and content of 100's of Newspapers/magazines.
- Also worked on miscellaneous tasks such as adding functionality to enable testing procedures or include custom scripts.

Bsquare

Trowbridge, UK 07/2022 - 06/2023

Student Software Developer

- For 6 months I worked in the development team for SquareOne in which I fixed bugs, produced new features (such as an OS updates page and a tour for a product) and tested code during QA sprints.
- For another 6 months I worked in the QA team, in which I wrote automated tests (for API and UI), performed manual tests and managed the delegation of manual testing during the QA sprint.

EDUCATION

University of Bath

09/2020 - 07/2024

Computer Science BSc - First Class Honours - Overall grade – 74.51%

Units including:

- Final year project (Dissertation) 71% titled "Human Involvement Can Improve Current Image Synthesis Methods within the Domain of Art" explored using human feedback to improve current AI image generation techniques in a manner similar to ChatGPT, this was implemented in Python.
- Logic and semantics of programming languages 81% I studied how category theory relates to the underlying logic of programming languages, including the lambda calculus and closed cartesian categories.
- Entrepreneurship 72% Working as a team we started a company and developed a business plan selling services within a student community.
- **Graphs and Networks: Theory and Applications** 73% I studied a Maths modules based around graph theory.
- **Reinforcement learning** 71% Working as a group, we implemented DQN, RAINBOW and PPO in Python to solve the lunar lander environment in OpenAI's gym.

- **Advanced graphics processing** 89% From scratch I developed a ray tracer in C++, implementing reflection, refraction and other lighting effects, to create a realistic generated image.
- **Safety-critical systems** 79% I studied case studies of system's shortcomings in relation to safety in the past and how to mitigate or prevent such problems in the future.

Chesham Grammar School

09/2013 - 06/2020

A level: Further Mathematics (A), Mathematics (A*), Computer Science (A), Physics (A).

GCSE's: 4 grades 9's, 2 grade 8's, 3 grades 6's, 1 grade 5, 1 grade A

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Experience with Vue, Swift, SwiftUI and PHP from Pugpig
- Experience with Angular, Selenium, and Gherkin from Bsquare
- Experience working in an agile environment and using Jira
- Experience with C++ and Java from my degree
- Experience with Python, Pytorch and Reinforcement learning techniques from my degree
- Experience with C and React from personal projects and hackathons
- Full UK driver's license

Personal Projects

- **Snowstorm** Created snow animations in a range of programming languages(Assembly, C, D, C++, Rust) as an exploration into graphics manipulation.
- Chrome Context Control Created a Chrome extension that allows user's more control over the right-click menu.
- **Traffic Simulator** Created a graphical traffic simulation in C, where rates of new cars arriving and how many are let through can be controlled.
- **Spotify Roulette** Created a web game in React, utilising the Spotify API, where users have to guess who a song belongs to out of a group of friends.

ACHIEVMENTS

- Volunteered at WorkAid for 18 months
- Gold DofE
- Competed in BathHack 2021 and 2024 using React both times producing web games.

REFERENCES

Alan Hayes

Personal tutor at the University AH347@bath.ac.uk

Hannah Stainer

Operations manager at BSQUARE HannahS@bsquare.com